BRADFORD JOHNSON - DATA ANALYST

Greenville, SC | 864-905-8853 | BradfordLJohnson@outlook.com | Linkedin | GitHub

SUMMARY

Data analyst and recent graduate of the Thinkful Data Analytics program. Proficiency with dashboarding, performance tracking, Pandas, Excel, SQL, Tableau, and Python to transform data into meaningful and easily understood visualizations and presentations. Experience in sociology provides an advantage to understanding problems and analyzing data.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software: R, Excel, Python, Tableau, SQL, PostgreSQL, PowerPoint

Tools: GitHub, RStudio, Quarto, Anaconda, pgAdmin4

Data Methods: Statistical analysis, data visualization, data cleaning, data exploration, data modeling, A/B testing

Additional Skills: Project management, business strategy, business intelligence, report generation

EXPERIENCE

Thinkful Remote

Data Analytics Program

06/2022 - Present

- Produced and presented professional projects and presentations focused on business forecasting, price modeling, and statistical analysis.
- Developed skill sets in data analytics systems including Pandas, Excel, PostgreSQL, Tableau and Python, and methodologies including dashboarding, performance tracking, data wrangling, cleaning, and analysis.
- Produced professional projects from concept to completion including:
 Business Analysis Revenue Growth Models Lariat Rent-A-Car | Link
 - Examined and cleaned historical sales data using Excel (VLOOKUP, pivot tables and t-tests).
 - o Facilitated exploratory data analysis and assessed by KPI performance.
 - o Developed and presented models that showcased a 40% increase in profits.

Statistical Significance - Fuel Economy - EPA Vehicle Data | Link

- Developed a model to assist shareholders in determining factors that drive fuel economy.
- o Supported data through t-tests run on housing price factors showing statistical significance.

Inventory Analysis - Sales Trends - Wine Reviews | Link

- Facilitated t-tests to determine the statistical significance between price, type and origin of wine.
- Developed visualizations in Python and presented data in PowerPoint to highlight inventory strategy to increase potential sales by 18% year over year.

TopGolf

Greenville, SC

10/2022 – Present

- Repair zones and target infrastructure improving game health for guests by 20%.
- Developed a process to increase confidence in RFID tag error identification by 60%.
- Conduct ad hoc analysis of game KPIs to identify issues and trends.

Maintenance Technician I

03/2022 - 09/2022

EDUCATION

Thinkful
Certificate, Data Analytics

Remote 06/2022 - Present

Winthrop University

Rockhill, SC 08/2017-12/2021

B.A. Sociology